Guide to the John Anthony Danaher Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
John Anthony Danaher papers
1900-1982
1938-1953
MS 165
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
36.25
(81 boxes)
The papers consist primarily of John A. Danaher's senatorial files and include political and constituent correspondence, speeches, background material, and copies of legislation. The files document Danaher's service on the Judiciary, Finance, and Banking and Currency Committees during the 76th-78th Congresses, and highlight his efforts to prevent American involvement in World War II, his study of post-war foreign policy aims, and his concerns over domestic liberties during wartime. The papers also contain files relating to Danaher's service on the Republican National Committee and Republican Party staff, and document his role as a campaign adviser to congressmen and to Dwight Eisenhower between 1945 and 1952. In addition there are also scrapbooks and files which document Danaher's pre-senatorial career. The papers contain no substantive material relating to Danaher's legal or judicial career.
Danaher, John Anthony, 1899-
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of John A. Danaher, 1968 and 1978-1979; gift of Ms. Sharon Danaher Henry, 2015.
Arrangement
Arranged in three series and two additions: I. U.S. Senate Correspondence Files, 1936-1945. II. U.S. Senate Subject Files, 1919-1953. III. General Files, 1916-1979.
Scope and Contents
The John Anthony Danaher Papers consist primarily of Danaher's files for his one term in the United States Senate (1939-1945). The files, which include political and constituent correspondence, speeches, back-ground material, copies of legislation, and clippings, document Danaher's service on the Judiciary, Finance, and Banking and Currency Committees. The papers highlight Danaher's efforts to prevent United States involvement in the war in Europe, his questioning of the aims of post-war foreign policy, and his actions to safeguard domestic liberty against possible incursions by the wartime government. The papers also contain files relating to Danaher's service as a Republican national committeeman, congressional aide, executive director of the Republican U.S. Senatorial Campaign (1948), and director of the special activities division for the 1952 Republican presidential campaign. In addition the papers include scrapbooks and a few files which document Danaher's pre-senatorial career.
The papers, which Danaher gave to the Yale University Library in 1969, 1978, and 1979, are arranged in three series and two additions: I. U.S. Senate Correspondence Files, 1936-1945; II. U.S. Senate Subject Files, 1919-1953; III. General Files, 1916-1979.
The first two series, which comprise the bulk of the papers, document Danaher's senatorial career; both contain materials on topics of Danaher's concern such as neutrality, lend-lease legislation, money and monetary policy, and Connecticut politics. The two series, however, include only a relatively small and select portion of Danaher's files from his senatorial office. At the time, Danaher left office in 1945 he had no place to deposit or preserve his files. He estimated that some six tons of material from 96 file drawers were destroyed. Series III contains material from Danaher's pre- and post-senatorial careers and relates primarily to his campaign efforts for the Republican Party between 1945 and 1952.
Series I, U.S. SENATE CORRESPONDENCE FILES, contains political and constituent correspondence, speeches, clippings, background material, political memorabilia, and legislation files, which are arranged according to a filing system established by Danaher's senatorial office staff. The system included ten filing categories: 1. General material; 2. JAD personal material; 3. Legislative files; 4. Position file; 5. Immigration and naturalization files; 6. Documents file; 7. Veteran's cases; 8: Bills introduced by JAD; 9. Post office; and Committee files, which were not given a numeric designation. The filing system is described fully in memoranda and notes included in folders 634 and 635 Portions of files 1-3, 8, and Committee files are included in Series I. The section heading General correlates with 1; Personal with 2; Legislation with 3; Bills with 8; and Committees with Committee files. Each section contains material from the 76th, 77th, and 78th Congress. The staff made pink cross-reference sheets to identify related material in other files. These are not comprehensive, however.
The General section includes cases, complaints, and inquiries concerning political and military affairs. The staff also made special files for important people and organizations and frequent correspondents. Many headings are topical and correspondence with friends and colleagues may be filed under a topical heading as well as a personal name. The files include correspondence with political associates such as Nathan Schatz, Raymond E. Baldwin, and J. Kenneth Bradley; representatives of the Connecticut press such as Maurice Sherman, Stewart Hoskins, William Downey, George Clapp, and Robert Byrnes; and Danaher's law partner Alex W. Creedon. Danaher's views on neutrality are reflected in correspondence with George K. Whitney of the Hartford America First Committee. Public response to Danaher's speech at an America First rally is included in folders 117-121. Edwin Borchard, of the Yale Law School, a well-known exponent of neutrality, acted as an adviser to Danaher on foreign affairs as well as Judiciary Committee matters. His correspondence is filed in numerous places in Series I but is concentrated in folders 63-65 and 152-153. For additional Borchard-Danaher material see the Edwin M. Borchard Papers (MS 670). Opposition to Danaher's isolationism is reflected in files for the Committee to Defend America by Aiding the Allies (folder 68), Connecticut United Nations Association (folder 177), and Eleanor Taft Tilton (folders 274-275a). For additional papers on this topic see the papers of the Hartford and Connecticut Chapters of the Committee to Defend America by Aiding the Allies (MS 66).
The Personal section includes some exchanges with Danaher family members, invitations, requests for autographs and photographs, and compilations of and quotes from Danaher's speeches. The section does not include any business or confidential correspondence.
The Legislative category was established by the staff for constituent correspondence on any legislation except that handled by one of Danaher's committees. The correspondence reflects public concern on neutrality issues, lend-lease proposals, conscription, and post-war foreign policy. Danaher's replies are often thoughtful reflections on issues and detailed explanations of his position. Correspondents include James Rowland Angell, Charles Beard, and Irving Fisher.
The Committees section documents Danaher's service on the Committees on Banking and Currency, Judiciary, Finance, and Patents. The files do not contain routine constituent correspondence; any correspondence present relates background information on proposed legislation. Many items were sent by the offices of other senators, the Department of Justice, or the Treasury Department. The files also include notices of committee meetings, agendas, hearing transcripts, and background printed material. There are sizeable files on the various war powers acts, insurance regulation, the Office of War Information, the Board of Economic Warfare, and the yearly tax bills. Folder 363 contains a daily diary showing Danaher's research and actions on one such piece of legislation.
The section Bills relates to very specific pieces of legislation introduced by Danaher. The files contain copies of the bills as well as correspondence pertaining to them.
The last section in Series I, Campaign 1938, contains the correspondence from Danaher's successful senatorial campaign, which is composed primarily of letters of congratulation and Danaher's acknowledgements. The files are arranged in weekly chronological divisions and correspondence is alphabetical therein. Correspondence is filed according to the date of Danaher's reply.
Series II, U.S. SENATE SUBJECT FILES; contains a small quantity of additional correspondence as well as more printed material, clippings, press releases, speeches, and legislative bills. This material is all, arranged by topic. The collected material represents a wide spectrum of political thought, and there are standard government and Republican Party publications, as well as pamphlets of politically active Catholic organizations; virulent anti-Semitic groups such as the American Tribunal; isolationist organizations such as American First; and pro-British groups such as Union Now. Although the series is not described in the memoranda of the office filing system some files contain the office's pink cross-reference sheets which locate similar topical material in other files. Major topics in the series include: U.S. foreign policy, neutrality, aid to the allies, banking and currency, Connecticut politics, monetary policy, and the Republican Party. These subjects are also reflected in the collection of Danaher's speeches filed in folders 677-690. Materials in folders 700-703 summarize Danaher's senatorial voting record. The folders contain sheets giving the outcome of voting on individual bills and Danaher's position. To these sheets Danaher often attached a memo to further record and explain the position he had taken.
Series III, GENERAL FILES, contains the only material in the papers documenting Danaher's pre- and post-senatorial career. The correspondence, printed matter, speeches, and scrapbooks primarily concern Danaher's work as a congressional and campaign adviser for the Republican Party. Campaign material is included in folders 712-735, 742-746, 750-751, 796-807, and 842 and in box 74. The Chronological section of the series includes some personal papers relating to Danaher's appointments to various offices, property, legal matters, letters of recommendation, and reminiscences. The scrapbooks in boxes 72 and 73 are the best source of information on Danaher's pre-senatorial career. Folders 808-809 also concern this period.
Biographical / Historical
John A. Danaher was born in Meriden, Connecticut on January 9, 1889. He graduated from Yale University in 1920 and was admitted to the Connecticut bar in 1922. From 1922 to 1934 he served as an assistant United States attorney in Hartford and from 1933 to 1935 he was secretary of state of Connecticut. Danaher was elected to the United States Senate in 1938 and served one term. Following his defeat for reelection in 1944, he resumed his law practice in Hartford and Washington, D.C. He remained an active adviser to Republican election campaigns from 1945 to 1952. In 1953 Danaher was named to a circuit judgeship on the United State Court of Appeals in Washington where he served until his retirment in 1969.
Catholics -- United States -- Political activity; Political campaigns -- United States; Elections -- Connecticut; Money -- United States; Neutrality; World War, 1939-1945; Connecticut -- Politics and government -- 1865-1950; United States -- Foreign relations -- 1933-1945; United States -- Politics and government; Judges; Lawyers; Legislators; Politicians; Public officers; Baldwin, Raymond E. (Raymond Earl), 1893-1986; Borchard, Edwin, 1884-1951; Bradley, J. Kenneth; Creedon, Alex W.; Danaher, John Anthony, 1899-; Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight David), 1890-1969; Schatz, Nathan; Sherman, Maurice Sinclair, 1873-1947; Tilton, Eleanor Taft; United States. Congress. Senate; America First Committee; Committee to Defend America by Aiding the Allies; Republican Party (U.S.: 1854- ); Republican Party. National Committee
- U.S. SENATE CORRESPONDENCE FILES, 1936-1945; Series I; 15.75 linear feet (39 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  This series is arranged in six sections: General; Personal; Legislation; Committees Bills; and Campaign, 1938. The first four sections are sub-divided further according to the Congress number.
  - General
    - 76th Congress
      - B, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - C, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Campaign tour, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Clark, Charles, 1936, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Clippings, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Connecticut flying cadets, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Connecticut labor, 1938-1939. (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Connecticut legislation, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Constitution sesquicentennial, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - D, 1937-1940 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Danaher, Francis, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Defense plans - inventions, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Defense program contracts, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Diplomatic immunity, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Easterbrook, Arthur, 1939-1941 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - F, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Federal Housing Administration, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - Foreign insurance companies, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      - H, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - Hillsmith Clarence, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - J, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - K, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - L, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - Lewis, Fulton, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - M - N, 1939-1940 (Box 2, Folder 25)
      - Mailing lists, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 26)
      - Marine Corps, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 27)
      - Morrison, C. A., 1940 (Box 2, Folder 28)
      - National Archives, 1940-1941 (Box 2, Folder 29)
      - National Catholic Welfare Conference, n. d. (Box 2, Folder 30)
      - Naval Reserves, 1939-1940 (Box 2, Folder 31)
      - O, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 32)
      - Ohio appearances, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 33)
      - R, 1938-1940 (Box 2, Folder 34)
      - Radio broadcasts, 1939-1940 (Box 2, Folder 35-39)
      - Receipted bills, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 40)
      - Republican National Committee, 1939-1940 (Box 2, Folder 41)
      - Republican Party, 1939-1940 (Box 2, Folder 42-45)
      - Republican State Central Committee, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 46)
      - S, 1939-1940 (Box 3, Folder 47)
      - Schatz, Nathan, 1939-1940 (Box 3, Folder 48-49)
      - Schools, 1939-1940 (Box 3, Folder 50)
      - Seismographology, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 51)
      - South America, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 52)
      - Speeches, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 53)
      - T, 1939-1940 (Box 3, Folder 54)
      - Timber, 1938-1940 (Box 3, Folder 55)
      - U.S. Senate and House, 1939, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 56)
      - V - W, 1939-1940 (Box 3, Folder 57)
      - War Department, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 58)
      - War trade, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 59)
      - Work Projects Administration, 1939-1940 (Box 3, Folder 60)
      - Y - Z, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 61)
      - Yachts and rescues, 1939-1940 (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - 77th Congress
      - Borchard, Edwin, 1939-1942 (Box 3, Folder 63-65)
      - Bradley, J. Kenneth, 1939-1942 (Box 3, Folder 66-67)
      - Committee to Defend America, Hartford, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 68)
      - Conflicts of interest correspondence, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 69)
      - Connally-Danaher remarks, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 70)
      - Connecticut judgeships, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 71)
      - Creedon, Alex W., 1939-1942 (Box 4, Folder 72-73)
      - Day, Pomeroy, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 74)
      - Early, Bernard, 1941-1942 (Box 4, Folder 75)
      - Faherty, Roger, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 76)
      - Fair Labor Standards Act, 1940-1942 (Box 4, Folder 77)
      - Gasoline rationing, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 78)
      - Higgins, Patrick J., 1941 (Box 4, Folder 79)
      - Hillsmith, Clarence, 1941-1942 (Box 4, Folder 80-83)
      - Hoskins, Stewart, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 84)
      - Hurlburt, Everett B., 1941-1942 (Box 4, Folder 85)
      - Jessup, Phillip, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 86)
      - Lewis, Fulton, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 87)
      - McCook, John B., 1942 (Box 5, Folder 88)
      - Miller, William, 1941-1943 (Box 5, Folder 89)
      - Morano, Albert P., 1941-1942 (Box 5, Folder 90)
      - National Railroad Adjustment Board, 1940-1942 (Box 5, Folder 91)
      - New London, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 92)
      - New York Inquirer, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 93)
      - Parker, Fletcher, 1941-1942 (Box 5, Folder 94)
      - Pentagon operations, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 95)
      - Personnel security questionnaire, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 96)
      - Radio, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 97-103)
      - Reciprocal trade with Canada, 1938-1941 (Box 5, Folder 104)
      - Religion in Russia, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 105)
      - Republican Party, 1941-1942 (Box 6, Folder 106-107)
      - Reserve officer training facilities, 1941-1942 (Box 6, Folder 108)
      - Rubber, 1942 (Box 6, Folder 109-111)
      - Salary limitation order, 1942 (Box 6, Folder 112)
      - Schatz, Nathan, 1941-1942 (Box 6, Folder 113)
      - Seismograph, 1940-1941 (Box 6, Folder 114)
      - Sherman, Maurice, 1941-1944 (Box 6, Folder 115)
      - Speeches, 1941-1942 (Box 7, Folder 116-123)
      - Steele, Thomas, 1939-1941 (Box 7, Folder 124)
      - Thomas, Norman, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 125)
      - Town Hall speeches, 1941-1942 (Box 7, Folder 126-130)
      - Transfer of offices, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 131)
      - United Service Organization, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 132)
      - War claims, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 133)
      - War Damage Corporation, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 134)
      - WBRY-radio, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 135)
      - Welfare and Recreation Association, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 136)
      - Westchester airports and apartments, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 137)
      - Whitney, George, 1941-1942 (Box 8, Folder 138)
      - Wilbur, Harry C., 1941 (Box 8, Folder 139)
    - 78th Congress
      - Air Corps training crashes, 1943 (Box 8, Folder 140)
      - Army cases
        - General, 1941-1944 (Box 8, Folder 141)
        - Clew, William, 1943-1944 (Box 8, Folder 142)
        - Galvin, William, 1943-1944 (Box 8, Folder 143)
        - O'Brien, Thomas, 1942-1944 (Box 8, Folder 144)
        - Young, Clarence, 1943-1944 (Box 8, Folder 145)
      - Army commissions (DeVaux, Reginald), 1942-1944 (Box 8, Folder 146)
      - Aviation, 1944 (Box 8, Folder 147)
      - Baldwin, Raymond E., 1943-1944 (Box 8, Folder 148)
      - Barge construction, 1942-1943 (Box 8, Folder 149)
      - Barnes, Puller, 1943-1944 (Box 8, Folder 150)
      - Beard, Charles, 1943-1944 (Box 9, Folder 151)
      - Borchard, Edwin, 1940-1944 (Box 9, Folder 152-153)
      - Bowles, Chester, 1942-1943 (Box 9, Folder 154)
      - Bradley, J. Kenneth, 1941-1944 (Box 9, Folder 155)
      - Briggs, Herbert, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 156)
      - Bureau of the Census, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 157)
      - Burke-Wadsworth bill (conscription), 1940 (Box 9, Folder 158)
      - Burton, Harold, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 159)
      - Byrnes, Robert, 1941-1942 (Box 9, Folder 160)
      - Censorship, 1942-1943 (Box 9, Folder 161)
      - C.I.O. in politics, 1943-1944 (Box 9, Folder 162-163)
      - Clapp, George ( New London Day ), 1942-1943 (Box 9, Folder 164)
      - Connecticut mineral resources, 1942, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 165)
      - Connecticut political campaign
        - General, 1943-1944 (Box 10, Folder 166-168)
        - Assignments, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 169)
        - Background material, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 170)
        - Congratulations and support, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 171-172)
        - Election expenses, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 173)
        - Election procedure, 1943-1944 (Box 10, Folder 174)
        - Expenses, postmaster correspondence, reprints, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 175)
        - Financial contributors, 1944 (Box 11, Folder 176)
      - Connecticut United Nations Association, 1944 (Box 11, Folder 177)
      - Creedon, Alex W., 1943-1944 (Box 11, Folder 178)
      - Crowley, Kathleen, 1941 (Box 11, Folder 179)
      - Cummings, Homer, 1937-1944 (Box 11, Folder 180)
      - Dahill, Edwin, 1943 (Box 11, Folder 181)
      - Danaher, John - policies, 1943 (Box 11, Folder 182)
      - Dawson, Thomas ( Metropolitan News ), 1943-1944 (Box 11, Folder 183)
      - Downey, William ( Farmington Valley ), 1944 (Box 11, Folder 184)
      - Foreign policy: printed matter, 1939-1944 (Box 11, Folder 185)
      - Hillsmith, Clarence, 1942-1944 (Box 11, Folder 186-187)
      - Hoskins, Stewart ( Lakeville Journal ), 1943-1944 (Box 11, Folder 188)
      - Hurlbert, Everett, 1942-1944 (Box 11, Folder 189)
      - Jackson, John ( New Haven Register ), 1940-1944 (Box 12, Folder 190)
      - Jefferson, Thomas, 1943-1944 (Box 12, Folder 191)
      - Keller, A. G., 1941-1943 (Box 12, Folder 192)
      - Larremore, Thomas, 1944 (Box 12, Folder 193)
      - Luce, Clare Booth, 1943-1944 (Box 12, Folder 194)
      - McMahon, Brien, 1944 (Box 12, Folder 195-196)
      - Marcello, Benjamin, 1940-1943 (Box 12, Folder 197)
      - Monetary policy - Spahr file, 1943-1944 (Box 12, Folder 198-199)
      - New England Council, 1944 (Box 12, Folder 200)
      - Palestine, 1943-1944 (Box 12, Folder 201)
      - Parker, Fletcher, 1942-1944 (Box 12, Folder 202)
      - Parker, Scudder, 1940-1944 (Box 12, Folder 203)
      - Phillips, John, 1943-1944 (Box 12, Folder 204)
      - Political
        - Democratic convention, 1944 (Box 13, Folder 205)
        - Election, 1943-1944 (Box 13, Folder 206)
        - Republican convention, 1944 (Box 13, Folder 207-208)
        - Republican Party, 1941-1944 (Box 13, Folder 209)
      - Prisoners of war, 1943-1944 (Box 13, Folder 210-211)
      - Public polls and opinions, 1940-1944 (Box 13, Folder 212)
      - Ready, Michael, 1943-1944 (Box 13, Folder 213)
      - Relocation of key industry, 1944 (Box 13, Folder 214)
      - Rittenband, Mrs. Nat, 1942-1944 (Box 13, Folder 215)
      - Ro - W
        General note
        See: box 17, folder 267-278
  - Personal
    - 76th Congress
      - A, 1939-1940 (Box 14, Folder 216)
      - B - C, 1939-1940 (Box 14, Folder 217)
      - D - E, 1939-1940 (Box 14, Folder 218)
      - Eye injury, 1940 (Box 14, Folder 219)
      - F - G, 1939-1940 (Box 14, Folder 220)
      - Form letters (Box 14, Folder 221)
      - H - I, 1939-1940 (Box 14, Folder 222)
      - International Peace, Carnegie Endowment for, 1940 (Box 14, Folder 223)
      - Invitations, 1939-1940 (Box 14, Folder 224)
      - L-P, 1939-1940 (Box 14, Folder 225)
      - Patrons, sponsors, memberships, 1939-1940 (Box 14, Folder 226)
      - Photograph(er)s, 1939-1944 (Box 14, Folder 227)
      - R - S, 1939-1940 (Box 15, Folder 228)
      - Speeches, 1940-1941 (Box 15, Folder 229)
      - Statements and opinions, 1938-1941 (Box 15, Folder 230-231)
      - Subscriptions, 1940 (Box 15, Folder 232)
      - T - Z, 1939-1940 (Box 15, Folder 233)
    - 77th Congress
      - A - E, 1942-1943 (Box 15, Folder 234)
      - Autographs, 1941-1942 (Box 15, Folder 235)
      - Biography, 1939-1943 (Box 15, Folder 236)
      - F - I, 1941-1943 (Box 15, Folder 237)
      - Invitations accepted, 1941-1943 (Box 15, Folder 238)
      - J - O, 1940-1943 (Box 16, Folder 239)
      - Office arrangements, 1938-1944 (Box 16, Folder 240)
      - P - Z, 1939-1942 (Box 16, Folder 241)
      - Portland centennial and well, 1941-1942 (Box 16, Folder 242)
      - Statements and opinions (JAD), 1941-1942 (Box 16, Folder 243-244)
      - Swift, Zephaniah, 1940-1941 (Box 16, Folder 245)
      - Voting record, 1942 (Box 16, Folder 246)
    - 78th Congress
      - A, 1943-1944 (Box 16, Folder 247)
      - Appointments, 1943-1944 (Box 16, Folder 248-250)
      - Autographs, 1943-1944 (Box 16, Folder 251)
      - B - I, 1943-1944 (Box 16, Folder 252)
      - Family, friends, outings, 1942-1943 (Box 16, Folder 253)
      - Invitations, 1943-1944 (Box 16, Folder 254-255)
      - J - L, 1941, 1944 (Box 17, Folder 256)
      - M - Z, 1943-1944 (Box 17, Folder 257)
      - Miscellanea, 1942, undated (Box 17, Folder 258)
      - Speeches, 1943-1944 (Box 17, Folder 259-265)